Well, I remember I I was 13 years old
and I was playing a game. Wolverstein,
Enemy Territory, it was called. I'm not
sure if you know it.
>> Wolfen.
>> Yeah, Wolstein. Yeah, like a first
person shooter. And uh we had a clan and
ever since my life, when I do something,
I want to do it as good as possible. I
played darts and I wanted to become like
a world champion in darts and I I played
football and I wanted to become the best
defender and I screwed up. That's why
I'm sitting here in this podcast.
>> This is your This is your failure mode.
>> Yeah, this is my failure mode. Yeah. I
even got songs on Spotify. So, if you
ever find me at a conference, okay, I
need that.
>> I wanted to become a DJ and I tried
>> to my to-do list. Welcome to Launched.
I'm Charlie Chapman and today I'm
excited to bring you the developer
behind the popular website and the
outstanding developer tool Rocketsim,
Antoine Vanderly.
>> Antoine, welcome to the show.
>> Thank you, Charlie. It's u an honor to
be here.
It's uh it's kind of funny. When I was
when I was doing prep, prep for people
I've known for a long time is always
weird because it's like I feel like I
know everything, but you're kind of
like, you know, going through the
website, refreshing yourself on things.
And I realized two very kind of funny
points here. I I've never thought of you
this way, but in a way, we're sort of
competitors or have been competitors on
two fronts at this point. Have you have
you thought about this before?
>> Yeah, I I think I think I know what you
mean.
>> Yeah. I again I don't actually think of
it this way but for a little while you
you had a uh interview podcast where you
were interviewing people. Yours was
significantly more ambitious than mine
because uh yours was like recorded in a
studio in person uh which I've done like
twice or maybe more than tw twice but as
has been cataloged on the show is
usually a failure and then I have to do
it virtually. And how long did how long
did that last? Well, I'm honestly
jealous on how you do it because it was
so hard to get people in Amsterdam into
the podcast studio. But I was like, if
it fails, it can only fail because it's
just not a success. It can't fail
because the level of quality was too
low. So, that's why I brought people in
and it brought the conversation in a in
the way I wanted it to do. The episodes
were great, but
>> yeah, it was it's very good. Uh, what is
the name of it? Is it is it the Swiftly
podcast or did it have a different name?
I'm trying to remember. the going in the
podcast basically going into the to the
course I was doing at that time and I
want to boost that that course with the
with the whole episodes and such but the
return on investment was just it took so
much time and I love doing the
interviews but the the after work and I
think you will recognize you know the
editing and the posting of the videos
and I mean I can do it but it was just
not the fun and yeah I don't know who
knows maybe maybe someday season 2 comes
back but I love that you're doing this
uh Charlie
>> yeah if you want to see uh this is weird
I sort of jumped the gun here, but I
just thought this was a funny uh funny
comparison. But yeah, if you want to see
what this show could be if I, you know,
put way more effort into it and was
better at uh basically everything, uh
you should go check out Going Indie cuz
yeah, it's uh it's pretty good. We'll
we'll put a link to, I guess, as a
dedicated YouTube channel, or is it your
normal YouTube channel? Yeah. But the
other one, which we'll get more into the
details on this later, but I've noticed
in your more recent developments on
Rocket Sim that like we're sort of
creating, we're coming at it from
different angles, but we're sort of
creating a similar similar app here.
Again, yours being the the much better
one, uh, in my opinion, but we'll get
into that. We'll get into that. So,
really quick though, minus what I just
was talking about, uh, I'm trying to
start the show now with a little bit a
quick explainer of what it is that your
app does. just an a quick elevator pitch
so that whenever I forget to do the real
intro later, people already have it in
their head. So, really quickly, uh what
is Rocket Sim? This is the single most
question that I got asked like plenty of
times and I always struggle to give the
proper answer to it because the thing is
it does 30 different things, right? So,
I have teams that that bless the
location simulation feature that other
teams don't even touch or know about,
right? So you could basically see it as
a Swiss uh knife and that that brings 30
plus features to the Xcode simulator
that might exist elsewhere but are just
hard to reach. Plus features that don't
exist at all in Xcode um that really
make the life of a developer much
easier. Testing features like push
notifications, accessibility, creating
recordings and screenshots and so on so
on so on. can mention all the 30
features, but I guess it just is really
focused on helping increase the
productivity of uh developers that work
with Xcode. And I'll I'll just say
without even explaining what a single
feature actually is, if you are a person
listening to this and you use the Xcode
simulator for literally any reason at
all, I guarantee you that it's worth
downloading and using uh Rocket Sim
because like one utility that probably a
half of your users, over half of your
users, there's a single utility that
makes it worth it for them. But there's
a whole bunch of those like you
mentioned and so we can get into it a
little more in the in a minute. But
yeah, this is one where it's like you
should literally just stop listening to
this and go download it and then come
back and listen to this.
>> Yeah, don't forget to come back. Yeah.
>> Yeah, don't forget to come back. But
yeah, for real, this is one of those
tools I've had for forever. Way before I
knew who you were, I think. So, yeah,
definitely recommend it. All right, so
to the to the regular show, before we
get into how Rocket Sim and your your
whole website and writing career and all
that thing uh took off, uh let's give
everyone an introduction to who you are.
So the three questions I always ask to
to kick off the show is uh where are you
from? Do you have a formal education
related to what you do? And then how did
you end up let's let's start with how
did you end up getting into swiftly?
Your your sort of writing.
>> Yeah, sounds good. So I'm Antoine
Fenderly. I'm from a very small village
called Spanuk. So if you're listening
from Spanuk, shout out. Um
>> it's a small village where?
>> If you went to Swift Island, it's a
conference on an island in the
Netherlands. You drive past it from
Amsterdam. So it's like a 30 minute
drive up north uh from Amsterdam. Yeah.
My my formal uh education is a
communication multimedia design. It used
to be
>> Oh, really? Okay.
>> Yeah. It used to be called interactive
media and it basically taught you about
how to create products like digital
products. So it taught me like yellow is
the first color a human processes or you
know you need to get to your end
destination within three clicks and all
those kind of things. But but this
podcast I'm going to pull on that thread
cuz I can't not What do you mean yellow
is the first color you process? I've
never heard this.
>> Yeah. So there's all kind of
psychological things, right? So if you
go to the supermarket, the entry is
actually slow on purpose because it
slows you down when you enter the the
supermarket and you will go slower
through the whole supermarket and you
will see more things. And then you'll
notice that the things on sale are
either yellow to get your attention or
they are red because it creates an
impulsive action. Those are all kind of
like tricks that you can use. And blue
from launched blue feels comfortable and
it works great with older people.
>> That was definitely what I was going
for. Yeah. Comfortable and old.
>> Uh
>> but I guess I guess the interesting part
of it is that I thought myself how to
code myself. I didn't really get lessons
on it, but at the same time, I got that
real big bag full of extra experience on
how to create great products. And I'm
I'm somewhere in the middle. I'm also
not a designer, right? Like I really
look up to Hit and B with with Helm
because it looks so beautiful and all
those animations. Um, but at the same
time, I have enough to at least make my
products look solid enough and make it
work in a way that you get things done
without realizing in a way. Okay, that's
interesting because we'll get to it in a
second, but at at some point you started
writing quite a bit about software
development and your your writing kind
of sits I wouldn't put it uh all the way
at the sort of Donnie Walls like really
deep technical but it's definitely on
the technical side. It's not like all
high level. So something about your
writing gave me the impression that you
had like a computer science background.
>> I think I'm I'm really good at teaching
myself how to code. So I I went quite
deep on it and eventually you know I'm
I'm building apps since 2009 so I got
quite a bag of experience and but but
still like when I write my articles I on
purpose try to not make it as deep as as
needed right like I leave out certain
details because I want both junior as
well as seniors learn what I think is at
least the most important for that topic
of the article and that might result in
articles that are not that in-depth
technical but they are much more
approachable for the wider
Um, that's the way how I look at
articles in a way.
>> And so, you already mentioned you've
been building apps since 2009. Did you
start doing that on your own or did you
get into like a company and that's how
you kind of got into it?
>> Well, I I remember I I was 13 years old
and I was playing a game uh Wolverstein
Enemy Territory it was called. I'm not
sure if you know it.
>> Wolf.
>> Yeah, Wolstein. Yeah. Yeah, like a first
person shooter. And uh yeah, we had a
clen and and ever since my life, when I
do something, I want to do it as good as
possible. I played darts and I wanted to
become like a world champion in darts
and I I played football and I wanted to
become the best defender and I screwed
up. That's why I'm sitting here in this
podcast. Thank God. Um
>> this is your this is your failure mode.
>> Yeah, this is my failure mode. Yeah. I
even got songs on Spotify. So if you
ever find me at
>> Oh, okay. I need
>> I wanted to become a DJ and I tried
>> to my to-do list. Uh dig these up. Yeah.
But either way, I was 13 years old and I
built a website for our clan because we
wanted to become the best clan possible.
And that's my first Yeah. start with
programming and that evolved in building
my first CMS in PHP because that's what
you do. And then I bought a phone which
was an Android because I couldn't afford
an iPhone. And then I had an internship
where I did Android development and
Windows phone development because they
needed people for that part.
You also did Windows phone development.
This is in the like Windows Phone 8, you
know, live tile era.
>> Or is this the
>> Oh, that I didn't realize we had this
shared background.
>> It was both of us basically.
>> That's so good. Honestly, the the way
you animations and stuff Oh, man.
>> Yeah. the the the API was definitely not
as mature as Android and iOS, but what
was there
>> was actually really nice minus Zam ZAML
horrible like trying to to do anything
custom. But if you lived within the
constraints of their UI system, uh it
was you could make some really nice
feeling apps, I thought.
>> Yeah. But let's not lose your listeners
because I think we will get off track if
we
>> No, there's dozens of us. Uh, all the
Windows fans are uh, Windows Phone fans
are rejoicing right now in their cars.
>> Yeah, I'm not sure if it's even still
alive, but either way, I I had a
colleague, a neighbor, colleague, so to
say. He was literally 2 meters next to
me and uh, he was doing iOS development
and I I always looked up to the iPhone.
I remember somebody walking with the
first iPhone that had a GPS and he could
walk us through the city. I was like,
"Oh man, I want that." you know and I
think I just tried to push myself into
that direction and eventually I was like
okay I want to work here but I want to
do iOS as well because I want to learn
that and yeah that's where where the
whole journey kind of kicked off.
>> Okay. So you you eventually worked your
way into an iOS job and you have like
typical iOS career going on. Where did
the the writing start then? Yeah, I
think um I was at a at an agency, a
fantastic agency here in uh in my
neighbor neighborhood so to say, a city
nearby and I wanted to speak at
conferences because I was like, well,
travel two cities and you know, for free
and meet people from the community. So,
I um I did talk proposals and uh did
another one and did another one. You
know, you know,
>> these are proposals, not actual talks.
>> I didn't get invited. Uh that was pretty
much the the the problem. And I I never
gave up, right? I wanted to become the
best speaker possible, right? That that
was kind of my personality. So I always
look at like, okay, what can I improve?
And if you looked at the conferences and
it's still a bit like that today, which
makes sense, you always see the same
familiar faces because those, you know,
sell tickets and you kind of know like,
okay, they know what they're speaking
about, so I want to go to that
conference. So I was like okay I need to
become that person that is you know you
want him to be at your conference
because tickets will be sold and that's
when I started to join I I joined with
transfer at that time and I remember
okay now I work at a company that
everybody knows so if I now do a talk
proposal I'll get accepted
I didn't get accepted right so quite
fast after that I decided to just write
about anything and I I figured like okay
consistency is key if I just write an
article every week and just do my best
possible version,
visitors will follow, growth will follow
and my first conference talk will follow
as well. And that basically happened
really quickly. I got like a proof of
the numbers growing and my blog went
really rapidly towards like 100,000
visitors per month or something like
that. And then that was search engine
optimization times, right, where you
could still really have an impact in
that sense.
>> Were you were you doing a bunch of
intentional SEO then? I mostly wrote
about the things that I knew people
would search for either way. Not so much
really. I didn't have like a tool to
look up for keywords other than search
console for example.
>> It was kind of your gut slash the Google
search console.
>> Yeah. As well as that, you know, I
didn't want to spend like a day writing
an article. So I wrote about things that
I learned that we transfer and that
resulted in many authentic articles that
people could relate to. Yeah. that that
got me quite rapidly into the whole
system of conferences and my first
conference talk was um at do iOS where
they knew I did a talk at the local
meetup. I had a talk ready and somebody
couldn't make it and I think I suddenly
remember that that person that couldn't
make it told me that he was the person
but I now don't remember who that person
was. Well, doesn't matter either way 24
hours before that conference started I
was called whether I could do that.
>> Wow, look at that. That's like a call up
in a you know major sports situation you
know like this is your chance your big
break.
>> Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. which was quite, you
know, I was nervous like crazy and you
know, I can still see my hand shaking
like like my first DJ gig had the same
kind of issue
>> cuz D iOS had a that was a pretty even
back then that was a pretty decent uh
sized audience, right?
>> Yeah. Yeah. I I was sitting at the the
speaker dinner I remember and I think
there were people like Daniel Steinberg
and the drop prompt stack overflow with
a lot of points I don't know his last
name people you look up to you know and
that felt great and at that point I had
a reference I spoke at a conference and
that already adds up if you want to
speak to another conference and that's
uh where the ball started rolling I
think and uh that's where where I'm at
now fast forward right like now I'm able
to speak at more conferences
>> so okay so your initial idea behind
writing was you had this sort of goal of
speaking at conferences, but that was a
while ago. You're still writing and as
far as I can tell, you're still writing
at least one article every week.
>> Every week. Yeah. It's a habit.
>> Significant, you know, commitment. So,
why are you still doing it now that
you've already achieved that original
stated goal? Like, what's the purpose of
it now?
>> Yeah. Yeah. So what I never realized at
that point is that eventually I um I got
at a point that I could ask money for
sponsorships and that started with small
numbers but eventually that grew and you
know we will talk about it but
eventually I created Rocket Sim and I
realized okay I basically have my
audience right here. I just have to send
an email to them. So I started the
newsletter and slowly but surely and and
you know eventually it allowed me to
really build up a side business that
really became became serious and I
managed you know I'm almost like do you
call it like artist I really I'm so
structured like like almost like crazy
structured and I think my my close
friends can confirm but it also made me
um made me that's why I can deliver an
article every week because I'm so
structured and I had a full-time job at
retransfer and I could still do it every
week and Yeah, in in 2024, that's two
years ago, after we transfer became more
corporate and wasn't so nice in my
progression reviews, I will save you the
details. I uh decided to work one day a
week on my my my website, my newsletter,
everything. And the impact of one day a
week was so crazy like the numbers went
up so rapidly because you can work on
more larger features, right? So that
rapidly
>> and I think an important piece of that
is I'm going to guess is being
structured because there's I know a lot
of people that like you know they quit
their full-time job or they negotiate
you know less not a full 5day work week
so they can dedicate a day to their job
and they'll find like oh I don't
actually get that much more done than I
was before. But it sounds like that
wasn't the case for you and I imagine
part of that is is the structure you
were building around it.
>> Yeah. Yeah. I mean so many people were
asking me like how do you manage all
those things that you do but it was
really like compound effect of all the
things that I had in place automations
you know turning repetitive task into
something that I could do in minutes
creating my own tools which nowadays you
know AI is a blessing for me because all
the things that I already did I can now
you know do 10 times faster but yeah
that that's also why I created my going
indie uh course right that's so if you
want to know how I did it everything is
in there I literally wrote down all the
tricks that I used and discipline in
planning. You know, whenever I had 10
minutes a day, I knew exactly what I was
working on. So, those 10 minutes were
spent so well that in a week I I could
still make a lot of progress even though
I had family, I played golf, and I I had
a full-time job and so on and so on.
>> And it's called going in going indie
because you did eventually go go
full-time indie. And we'll I promise
we'll get into Rocket Sim, but at the
time that you went indie, and correct me
if I'm wrong because this is just from
my memory of us talking. Your primary
income was swiftly the website
newsletter, right? More than rocket sim.
>> I was in a situation where I matched my
we transfer salary, which was above
standards in the Netherlands for for you
know, all the stuff iOS engineers. So
the risk was pretty much zero in terms
of income. And I at that moment that I
went full India, we were just we just
had our second son a week ago. I was
kind of like, okay, that delivery needs
to go well and if that's all good, then
I'll just go
>> for clear.
>> Paternity leave, you know, I had some
extra time to to work on the kickstart
of my my indie journey. But yeah, the
the newsletter, the sponsorships, but
Rocket Sim was doing pretty well. I
think it was close to 100k recurring
revenue a year as well at that point.
>> Okay. Okay. So, it was I mean it was
properly taking off by that point. I
couldn't remember. I mean it was on that
curve. I just didn't remember where it
was at that time.
>> It was pretty far. And on top of that, I
knew the impact of the single day a
week, but I also knew that I had so many
ideas that I didn't step into yet
because of the time constraint that that
was another thing that I really did,
right? Like I couldn't work on new apps.
I couldn't work on new projects because
I do everything on the side. I need to
keep my focus. But now, and that was
also a risk that I realized afterwards,
like I suddenly had five days a week and
I let loose of all the things that I
learned as a side hustle. So, I didn't
prioritize anymore. I didn't
>> Oh, so when you when you suddenly had
more time, you did run into that problem
I was describing.
>> Yeah. Crazy.
>> Oh, interesting. Okay.
>> Yeah. So, I I went starting on my own
course because now I had the time to do
courses, right? So, I I figured, okay,
let's let's go with going indie because
that's knowledge I have in my head. I
can basically create the course without
thinking. And then I realized like what
I'm now explaining I'm no longer doing.
I should get back on track. It's stupid,
right?
>> Oh, that's really funny. Okay.
>> Yeah. You don't you don't think about
it. You you're like, well, you have so
much time. So, I kind of ended up in a
situation where I felt like, okay, I
have so much time. I can do everything
that I started doing everything, which
made me less focused on the things that
I should actually do. So the impact of
what I did was still big and impactful
because I I did more things, but I could
do so much more if I really focused. So
I I really had to kind of like level up
myself again.
>> Interesting. And really focus in that
case was limiting the scope of what
you're doing and instead
spending more time on on a smaller
amount of things.
>> It's a bit of both. And honestly, I had
the same situation like November
December last year because of AI. You
kind of have the same thing. you can now
do much more at the same time, right?
And it's it's kind of like the same
thing as what happened back then because
you you gain more not necessarily more
time with AI, but you gain more
possibilities, right? There are
basically no limitations on your
creativity anymore. So, I'm constantly
kind of like getting back to my own
course and my own fundamentals to really
put myself back on track. There's a
television show that I love watching
which is Dragons Dragon's Den. I think
every country has a different name for
it, but you basically have four
investors sitting watching
>> it's a shark tank in in America.
>> That's what I mean. And I remember one
of the Dutch sharks, I think I have to
say then um
>> you can say dragons.
>> Dragons. Okay.
>> Sounds more fun.
>> Okay, let's do it. So, one of the Dutch
dragons. I I always think about it, but
he said like, okay, to somebody that did
a pitch, you do too much things. you
have a pitch right here for a company,
but at the same time, you have a
full-time job. I'm not going to invest
in you. But the the real real point is
that focus, right? And if I focus on
Rocket Sim, Rocket Sim goes super well.
If I start a new app, I can clearly see
Rocket Sim doing less. And it's because
I don't talk much about it at that
point. I don't post social post about
it, right? Like it's not a living thing
at that point. So, it all makes sense,
>> especially in your case or anybody who's
indie more or less on their own. Uh it's
it doesn't go on without you because
you're pretty much entirely the driving
force behind the thing. Uh and then one
more thing about the writing and then
we'll we'll go backwards, roll back in
time and get to Rocket Sim. Uh I'm
really curious about, you know, we
talked about AI already, but like I've
definitely been hearing across the board
the the squeeze on coding educational
content in particular. And now your
writing does kind of stretch the gamut
between like there is a bunch of
technical coding stuff but then there's
a lot of like sort of business and indie
development stuff but are you feeling
that same that same squeeze where
there's less people coming in uh
especially on the search side of things?
>> Yeah 100%. So this is also a
relationship to November December right
when when I started to realize like okay
I need to reinvent myself. I um I was
part of a growth accelerator program
from the platform that I host the course
at and that brought me like on one
coaching session every month and the
person at a certain point asked me like
where do you want to be next year and I
told told her like well I'm not thinking
about next year I'm thinking more about
two three years from now because the
actions I do today kind of like create
that path towards me in three years and
I told her like my business now is
evolved around my blog and my newsletter
and the blog is dying
clearly, right? Like
>> so you're seeing that same that same
trend then
>> 100%. I think it's not a surprise,
right? Like instead of going to a
Swiftly article, having to read through
the details and you can now just ask AI
to do the thing for you and
>> probably trained on the details you
wrote.
>> Yeah. Well, honestly, I started creating
my uh my own agent skills with my own
content because I was like, well, if AI
grabs it either way, I might as well
>> take advantage,
>> do the job myself. Yeah, take advantage
and and help the community with a with
an agent skill that I believe is the
best for for their purpose, right? But
at the same time, I also realized like
the companies that sponsored me still
have the need to reach the audience and
my newsletter might become even more
valuable to them because nobody visits
websites anymore, right? So the focus
was kind of like moved a little bit more
towards the newsletter and the articles
are still being read. But you might also
notice if you're a frequent reader of my
articles that I focus much more on
practical AI much less on coding details
because the coding details you know
you'll you'll learn but how to pick the
right agent skill out of many right or
how to use an MCP to to load revenue
data and optimize your onboarding to
watch the payw wall right like th those
are I think much more practical things
that you'll receive and as soon as I
made that shift I I think my my
followers on Twitter for example grew
like from 63,000 to 69,000 in 2 months
or something.
>> And you think a lot of that is kind of
the the sort of AI hype like you're sort
of jumping on this big movement that's
happening and you can kind of grow with
it
>> kind of. Yeah. Also because I'm I'm
fully in it, right? Like there's
founders of companies that worry because
there are small people like me that
suddenly can do what they do with 200
people, right? I'm on the on the good
side, I would say. like I'm an indie
developer and I just hired 20 agents
that do work for me every day. And while
I'm on that journey, I just I'm keeping
a diary of all the things that I learn u
because I'm also working on like a new
course on AI fundamentals. I really want
to make that kind of like my new journey
in a way because I feel like the blog is
dying. Sponsorships will stay because I
have a newsletter, but the newsletter
needs to keep growing and I don't think
it will keep growing if I start writing
about how to use guard in Swift, for
example. Right. So,
>> yeah. Well, and there's kind of like,
you know, if you're thinking of it that
you're competing with the LLMs, you're
not going to like it's just almost
impossible to imagine competing with LM
on like technical content like that. But
where you can compete is it doesn't
matter if every LLM has the exact same
information that you wrote about your
personal experience. What they don't
have and literally can't have is the
fact that the personal experience
happened to you. They can't write it
from personal perspective. And so that's
like that is almost the the one kind of
differentiating thing that no matter how
good these things get uh you always have
at least that human element sort of by
definition.
>> Yeah. But it is ironic in a way because
the AI agents we have today are trained
on the data from bloggers like me but at
the same time they kill the bloggers
that train their data. So
>> I was just talking okay this is this is
another little tangent. I was just
talking to somebody about this same
phenomenon and I'm like I think if I
were to project out where this goes, I
think the the only path I can imagine is
the only the incentives are going to
have to lie in the like language and
platform creators to fund this. So
either that means they have to pump a
lot more money into their own
documentation which they assume is not
going to actually be read by anybody but
is like basically for LMS to consume or
they fund they are the ones who fund
external writers and bloggers and stuff
but that almost feels like the only path
that this could eventually lead to in
terms of in terms of the like technical
content kind of thing.
>> Yeah true. No. Well, I've been involved
in some I think it's Cloudflare. Um,
they are working paper crawl. There's a
HTTP status code that has never been
used, but now it will be used again that
returns I'm not sure which one it is,
but then it basically says to the agent,
well, you're happy to read Antoine's
article, but you need to pay for this
crawl, and it's about 00001
cent or something. But with a lot of
crawls, the authors basically get paid
back. But yeah, that's I didn't really
think through that like that specific
thing feels like maybe but an evolution
of that maybe it's like Spotify kind of
model which isn't exactly the most
appealing maybe to get turned into that
being the business model on the artist
side if you will but I mean honestly
like the things that I write are mostly
also in the Apple documentation right so
I'm fine if they use it and um it's it's
also you know I wrote the articles for
my own learning process as well personal
knowledge base that I could revisit
myself and if I can continue with my
newsletter and and teach the practical
stuff that I learn every day via my
articles, then I'm I'm really in a happy
ground for the future ahead, I would
say.
>> Yeah. And I like I think that's the the
right way to think about it. I mean,
there's probably people that maybe it's
good that there's people that are
fighting the good fight or trying to
build these big systems, but if you're a
creator, like really you should just be
thinking about, okay, how can I
differentiate? How can I provide value
that people I can still build a business
on and continue forward? And it sounds
like that's kind of what you've got
going with in the newsletter world.
Seems like it's this kind of crazy
exploding market right now, right? In
terms of journalists moving to personal
newsletters like that idea of paying for
that kind of content or or in your case
it being sponsored. This is uh it seems
like it's a a growing field sort of
funny enough as the blog side of things
is shriveling.
>> Yeah. I mean the tools improve, right?
like it's so much easier to now launch a
newsletter and you don't have to pay
like crazy amount for a thousand
subscribers anymore because the
competition is just higher. So I think
it becomes all much more approachable
and I think they also realize like if
you retain your audience right like if
you have a way to repetitively talk with
your audience via an email you are much
more likely to surface them the course
that you have or the products that you
sell. And I think that's something that
many artists see as well in a way. Yeah,
I guess it is. It's sort of like the
influencer economy in a way where, you
know, most of them aren't really making
that much money on the actual creator
payments from the the platforms. It's
more the figuring out other ways to sort
of monetize that audience. Um,
>> yeah, while integrity and all that.
>> What's that?
>> They don't own the audience. I think
that's the biggest problem, right? like
if you're on Instagram or on Twitter or
anything like you can have so many
followers but the platform decides
whether those followers will see your
link to the course and they don't like
linking to external places right so the
best way is to really focus on getting
those emails and and staying connected
with your audience via that platform
yeah
>> yeah but the other way that you can kind
of build a foundation for your financial
security is doing something that's not
writing uh at all and you know would
never be disrupted by AI and that's
coding your own app.
>> Yeah. So, RocketSim uh has been around
for quite a while, but let's like roll
back to where did it start?
>> Yeah. Well, I I kind of told it a little
bit before, but I love creating my own
apps, right? Like Rocket Sim happens to
be an app that I shared in in the app
store, but I also have an app for my
newsletter, for my website, right? Like
I have all this kind of internal tools.
But it was 2019
I worked on we transfer and we transfer
was a file transferring app. You
basically upload files you get a link
you share a link with another person and
that person can use the same app to
receive it. So we had all kinds of
transfers that we needed to test in the
simulator. And the one thing that I did
was a venderly.com/html
page with deep links to easily open
those deep links on the simulator. But
you know I every time I had to open
safari, open that URL and after the
simulator is reset I need to remember
that domain name and it was just you
know repetitive and I wanted to improve
my productivity. So I started working on
rocket sim status bar app. The only
thing it could do is storing deep links
and open that in uh in the active uh
simulator.
>> So it was a it was a status bar app like
it lived in the menu bar
>> and what it was just a drop down with
links and if you clicked on it it would
I guess there's there's CLI commands
where you can like trigger actions
inside of the the simulator.
>> Exactly.
>> Yeah.
>> Okay. So that was how it literally
started.
>> Yeah. Exactly. So for those that don't
know, Xcode uh ships with sim control,
siml, and you could basically say rocket
sim is a very advanced wrapper nowadays
around that simulator tool. But yeah, it
already existed back in the days and
there was one command that allowed to
execute deep links in the in the
simulator and I basically allowed you to
create groups for a certain bundle
identifier so you could launch those
deep links in a specific app for your
needs.
>> And you built that for yourself. Did you
did you start distributing it right
away? Was it distributed internally in
Wii transfer or did you like think, hey,
maybe people would be interested in this
and you started you released it kind of
publicly?
>> Yeah, it started to grow slowly but
surely, right? Like I I basically had a
I that's the thing with app IDs. You
need to get the ball rolling and at a
certain point I had that app in place.
So whenever I had a new ID that I could
automate, I could basically just add it
to that same project. And before I knew
that app evolved into many more useful
features that I could use myself during
my day-to-day job at we transfer.
>> So you just kept shoving new simulator
utilities in there because it was
sitting there.
>> Yeah, exactly. And and it's still like
that today. Like you don't want to see
the road map that I have. I have a
public repository with 198 open issues,
but I also have a private repository
with 100 IDs that I have myself that I
keep for myself because I don't want
anyone else to build it.
>> Yeah. Yeah. Yeah,
>> it's it's how it goes. But um for the
first two years, it didn't make any
money. It wasn't really meant for that.
I was
>> So you did you did release it publicly
though.
>> Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. I think
>> store initially or did you do it like
externally at first?
>> Yeah. No. No. I never I I once tried but
sparkle was so difficult to do and
nowadays it's it's so much easier. But
you know out of the app store
distribution was difficult. Plus, I I
also wanted to benefit from the contacts
that I had at Apple. And I felt like if
I go into the app store, I could
probably get featured or or you know,
it's also a developer tool. And I still
say this today to many clients that ask
ask about security certificates and all
those kind of things, right? Like Rocket
Sim is in the app store. It's sandboxed.
It runs on your local machine and we
don't share any data to backend
services, right? It creates a certain
feel of security which is super
important if you start asking for
permissions about the developer
directory and derived data and those
kind of things.
>> Yeah, that's a good point.
>> Yeah. So, yeah, it was in the app store
day one basically and the first version
weren't weren't that that serious,
right? But eventually I added
screenshots and and recordings and the
simulator didn't offer that to be clear.
Give support. You couldn't upload videos
to GitHub pull request yet. So having a
way to really quickly create a recording
into a gy was quite unique back in the
day. So that was
>> I can I can personally attest to the
number of uh copies that me using it and
then pushing it on people because I was
putting it into GitHub PRs. Uh yeah,
that that that was definitely a feature
that people jumped on to especially when
you added in the ability for it to show
touches. So, like as you're recording in
the simulator, you know, as you're
clicking around, when you export it out
in Rocket Sim, it can put a little
circle that represents, you know, where
the person's finger was touching. And
that, man, does that is that amazing for
communicating, you know, what is
actually happening. Just rapid, massive
difference. And putting that in your
PRs, especially if it's one that you're
trying to convince people is worth
doing. Like that little extra polish. It
sits inside of a frame. It's got these
touches that can go a long way.
>> You only realize once you used it once,
right? Then you suddenly you can follow
along what the person is doing, right?
Without even hearing any voice or or
whatsoever. Yeah. Especially so it's not
only showing touches, right? It's
constantly showing where your mouse is
at. So it's kind of like touch attention
mode I like to call it. But um you can
really similar to like if you're
recording a tutorial uh on, you know, a
Mac or whatever and you use the mouse to
kind of circle around something. It's a
little different than that, but it's
Yeah, it's that idea. It's like before
they tap on a button, you see it move up
to that button and it kind of draws
their eye to like I'm about to take an
action in this area. Pay attention here.
>> Exactly. Yeah. You can just easily
follow along. And there were things in
the simulator like if you recorded like
landscape, it would still come out of
this portrait. Like the the recording
feature was really bad and Yeah. in the
in the built-in simulator. And they
improved later which also improved
rocker sim directly because I was
relying on the same underlying
structure. But this kind of shows like
how I was thinking, right? Like I wanted
to have those recordings myself, so I
created it. I wanted to have those
screenshots myself, so I created it. I
wanted to have location simulation. I
wanted to have quick access to the
common directories like the caches
directory or the file storage directory.
And
>> dive data just that that also is one
that sells people. Uh it's just a quick
way to get to your drive data folder. Uh
weirdly an annoying thing to get to uh
to clear out.
>> Yeah. And and what's a blessing and a
curse is that the things that I built
are not written on Stack Overflow and
and AI doesn't know the answer. I I
really have to find my own answers and I
still have to do it. It goes a little
faster now with AI, but many of the
things like releasing in the app store
was not easy. You you can't just access
the simulator control terminal command,
right? So I had to figure out a way to
do that in the app store while being
sandboxed. All those limitations. It's
secure. That's a great selling point,
but in terms of being sandboxed as a
developer tool,
>> it'd be a lot easier if you could just
do literally whatever you wanted.
>> Yeah, I still see myself like, you know,
one of those moments that I've give up.
And then fully January, I tried to build
Sparkle and I was like, "Okay, screw the
app store. I'll just go ahead." And I
I just couldn't
I needed to be in the app store. So, I I
kept pushing it. And, you know, now I
know the tricks and I kind of like find
found my way through. And I'm not
getting any exceptions by the way. I
really have to deal with the same
sandbox limitations everyone has to. But
yeah, uh the fun part of it is that I
remember the network speed control. So
that was something I really wanted to
build. I hated the network link
conditioner because it would also slow
down your Mac, right? So, you're working
on
>> and just for just so everyone who's not
a developer understands like in in your
simulator and on your device, you can uh
in your developer settings, you can go
to a setting and turn on what's called
network link conditioner, which
literally just artificially slows down
your internet connection. But if you do
that on your Mac while you're building
it, it also slows down if you're
googling something or whatever. And
every developer at some point in their
career has had a time when their
internet was running really slow and
they were annoyed and they realized it
was cuz they just left that turned on.
>> Exactly. Very annoying.
>> Those those pains. Yeah. And this was
also a time where there was no AI,
right? So every single answer you would
basically find on Staflflow. So you're
working on slow networking support and
you go to Stack Overflow, but it's also
slow. Well, you know, it's painful. But
I I remember I I I created that issue
like okay I want to create a solution
that works just for the simulator and
that issue has been open for two years.
I just couldn't find the answer. And
every now and then I just revisit that
that list of issues, right? You you grow
as an engineer, there are new APIs, you
get to talk with people at Dubdc, you
post on the Apple forums, and you hope
for an answer. It's much better
nowadays, by the way, but back in the
days, it was tricky to get the answers
that you needed. And at a certain point,
I found a way to do it. And the moment
that it worked was so amazing because I
was literally thinking about it for two
years. And now I'm able to just slow
down exactly like the network link
conditioner just your app in the
simulator without affecting your Mac
which in AI days is even better right
you can just use AI still on rapid fast
internet. Yeah and that's one example
and I have many of those and like I said
it's a blessing and a curse because it's
not easy to copy Rocket Sim. Um I I see
more and more people creating like an
app for screenshots and videos.
Hey, now they're different. They're
different.
No,
>> it's it's it's totally fine. I love that
actually, right? Like, um, you know, the
thing is with competitors or or friends
that also built a similar app, I don't
want to call you a competitor because I
don't look at it that way.
>> Yeah. to be clear and I I don't even
know if I've mentioned it much on this
podcast, but I have a I have a Mac app
that's it's like a toy app really uh
called Frameus and it the point of that
app is screenshots for me at least
screenshots that you take on your real
device. You can just drag into it and it
wraps it in a frame and you can export
it. But I keep adding more features and
I just started adding a feature to where
screen recordings that I take. You can
add you can artificially add uh swipe
and tap indicators largely because I
find myself wanting what I can do in
Rocket Sim on my real device screen
recordings and I can't. It's not as good
as what you can do in Rocket Sim. But
they're they're really they're really
different things. But it was very funny
seeing in one of your recent
newsletters, uh, and we can maybe talk
about this if you want to, but like
you're building like a full-blown video
editor for the screen recordings. And
like looking at it, I'm like, man, this
is like a nicely designed version of the
sort of hacky thing that I'm building,
which is really funny. But again, they
are different like uh they are different
things.
>> Yeah. And I mean the way I look at you
know like there are also many other blog
creators and there are many other
developer tools and there are plenty of
tools for ASO and the thing is like the
restaurants that are combined together
in a single place do much better than
the restaurants all distributed across
the city. And there is a reason because
people want to go to a central hub and
then have a choice in a way. And the way
I look at it with apps is that people
might get into your app and they realize
like oh wait a second I can actually
create a video with device vessel and
you educate them about the fact that
that's possible and then they find
rocket sim and they see like rocket sim
does it as well and they install rocket
sim could also be the other way around.
they are a user of rocket sim and they
actually want to have the same feature
but then for uh for a real device and
you've been such user and you decide to
build that yourself but there might be
another Charlie that decides like okay
let's see what's out there and they
notice your app right so I think
embracing competitors is something that
that might not be the first thing you
think about but actually if you if you
work together and I also do that with my
newsletter by the way I have a content
kit or a comfort kit creators iMessage
group where many newsletters of the
community are in and we promote each
other because they might find an
audience and they subscribe to their
newsletter and they promote my
newsletter. But I also bring in people
and we help each other grow and I'm very
much like to look at it that way and
help the community work together if that
makes sense.
>> Oh yeah, definitely. And my favorite
like there's a number of these in the
the iOS sort of indie community of like
competing developers who are very
friendly with each other. Um, and I have
that actually a little bit in the the
sort of white noise space. There's a
couple developers that if they run into
some sort of bug that's really esoteric,
clearly they're using my app to be like,
"Is this us or is this a framework
thing?" And if they find a solution,
I've had people just DM me solutions to
problems I didn't even know were
problems because they fixed it on their
end and they're like, "Hey, just so you
know, this is an issue." And it's like,
man, that's a really encouraging
environment and it makes you want to,
you know, encourage them and help them
in any way that you can, too. So, uh,
>> yeah. And what I also learned over the
years is because I I had to learn this,
right? Like in the beginning, there were
some other developer tools and I was
like, well, I don't want you to build
something like that as well. But
honestly, people will find out either
way. So, you might as well just be the
the good person there and help each
other out and the favor will be
returned, right? Sometimes you have
friends that you you you give input to
for years and you feel like okay I'm
just that solo friend that just gives
and gives and gives but one day they
will come back and give back to you and
then it's all worth it in a way and
that's the same with this right so yeah
it's difficult mindset sometimes for
people but I think together you will
grow much faster
>> I think both of us are in this in this
category too where it's like we're
trading on our goodwill to a degree as
well right like part of rocket sim
success is the product marketing itself
and you you know trying all the
different things that you've tried in
terms of marketing but a big part of it
is you have an audience who trusts you
likes you knows you as a person and they
want like I again I'm pretty sure I
found rocket I don't remember the order
of operations of whether I found
Rocketsim or you first but I didn't know
you personally at that point right but
since I've gotten into this community
there's so many apps that I've started
using because I'm friends with the
person or I like them online or whatever
and then it becomes part of your
workflow and the reason I like them in
the first place is cuz they're they're
good and they they make good stuff. And
so it is to that point, but like you can
get a lot of mileage out of just not
being the jerk in the room.
>> Yeah. And for people listening that
think I'm uh they are afraid to talk
with me, please don't be afraid. I'm the
>> No. Antoine in person is is quite a
imposing jerk really. Uh you know, he
smiles. All of his smiles are only for
the camera. As soon as the camera's off,
it's just angry. I I I visit conferences
and I once went to a conference and the
speakers were like afraid to take
hostage of my time and were really like
well yeah I just wanted to say hello and
and I'm like I'm I'm here to drink a
beer with you all like that's why I'm
here
>> right like that's why I'm here right so
yeah I don't know it's sometimes the the
serious side of being online and just
posting serious articles and content.
Um, and that's also why I started to
post more pictures of my chickens and
dog, by the way, to make me, you know,
I'm a person. I'm not a robot. You know,
I make mistakes. Yeah, I'm I'm real. Uh,
that's funny. So, okay. So, we talked
about like why you built it. You put it
on the store right away and you've been
just sort of pouring ideas into it over
time based a lot on what you want. But
at the time, at least where you left
off, it wasn't like a business. So, when
did that transition happen? like did you
was it something you did or did
something happen that sort of kicked
things off and then you started taking
it more seriously?
>> Yeah. Yeah, there were a few phases
right. So in the Netherlands you can be
an ammon sack which is basically a sole
entrepreneurship uh without having
certain tax responsibilities and such
and for a while that was good enough
when I was working at we transfer but at
a certain point you make more money you
need to pay more taxes so you convert it
into a real company and that was for
everything I earned right so swiftly and
and rocket sim and everything alto
together and everything grows slowly but
when I went working like one day a week
on mostly rocket sim that's where I went
from 1,000 MR monthly recurring revenue
to I think in one year to 4,000. So
that's four times.
>> What was that that caused that? Was it
the development you were doing like
features or were you doing marketing
along with that?
>> I think mostly the features because I
can sell so many more things. I can post
100 more tweets but if the value in the
product is not there it will not bring
in anything. Right. So the the main
reason was that I could work on features
like the network speed control or the
network monitoring and those those
larger features that you simply have to
build with a bit more long longer focus,
right? Like three four hours of focus
instead of just 10 minutes a day because
that was literally what I did before,
right? Like 10 minutes 30 minutes. Um 10
minutes always turn into 30 minutes by
the way. It's all about getting
>> Oh, yeah. Yeah. Yeah. 10 minutes is 30
minutes. Yeah. Clearly.
>> Yeah. I I run through the same thing
with dark noise stuff. It's like there's
these big features that I'm like, I'm
going to need like this dedicated, you
know, 4hour coffee work night to do
that. And it's like, well, how often
does that happen when you have kids and
a family and a job where you're
traveling a lot? And so you you pick off
lots of these little features
constantly. So, you're always doing
stuff, but it's like the big ones that
you know will move the needle take
dedicated time.
>> That's exactly what it is. And there's a
feature in Rocket Simar feature. There's
a road map view where you can vote on
stuff. And I always knew a bit like what
people wanted. And the big one on the
list was the network monitoring. So it's
basically like uh Charles proxy or proxy
man for the simulator that always runs
in the background. So whenever you have
that unexpected failure of a response,
it's running in the background. You open
up, you'll copy the request to your
backend developer and it's fixed right
away. That was number one on that
roadmap list. And I remember it was June
or July or something and I I got it
working and I released that and I think
I generally had like 40 running trials
or something and then I peaked towards
120 at that point which really just
proves like if you build what your users
want you know the the real fields will
follow if
>> I do think that your kind of like I said
at the beginning your app is a little
unique in that most apps features you
add can have a make a big difference in
terms of how good the app is or how
users will stick with it. But the actual
pitch for the app, it can't be that
wide, right? Like if you if you build
like Straa, you know, running tracking,
it's like it can have a trillion
features. And that matters for users
staying with it or not leaving for a
competitor, whatever, but you can't put
all those features in your sort of
advertising. And it's not really going
to draw very few features are going to
draw people. But your app because of
your audience, you can make this one
esoteric feature and that's a new
marketable thing that could bring in
somebody who does not care about a
single other feature of your app, but
they will 100% pay for that one feature
because it changes their workflow. You
know, they're a uh performance engineer
on a principal like engineering team
that isn't building features. their only
job is to ek out the best performance
they can for users when they're have low
internet connectivity or whatever. Like
that's a job that lots of people have.
If you have a feature that makes their
life easier, they're going to pay a
subscription just for that. They don't
care about screenshot recordings and all
that stuff.
>> Exactly. And and this still happens as
of today. So I I got a running test
flight beta now with way too many
things. Blame AI, but it's good. It's
getting there. But one of the features
>> What was your thing about focus uh being
a big thing you need to be doing? There
is focus, but I I just have focus on 10
different agents. So,
>> Oh, yeah. I see. Yeah, I'm focusing. I'm
completely 100% focused on 10 different
things.
>> It's all rocket sim.
>> That's fair. That's fair.
>> To be frank, that that is something I
learned because if you do many things
with agents and you want to do a lot of
things, then at least make sure it's the
same context, the same project. That
makes things so much easier. No, but I I
had that breakthrough thing once again
which allowed me to do 120 frames per
second recordings with the simulator
plus voice over overlay and so it's like
showing all the voiceover elements on
top of the simulator and you can
navigate as if you're using voice over
but you don't have to use your actual
physical device. And the the point I
want to make is that I got emails from
people that used rockersim one two years
ago and then kind of not really used it
anymore. They that just happens when you
need a network monitor but you're not
really working with networking anymore.
You and there's plenty of reasons for it
but they emailed me like yeah when I saw
this feature I'm getting back to it you
know I want to have access to the test
flight. So it's literally what you just
mentioned like that one feature can
bring people back or bring new people
in. It's really yeah it can make a
difference in hours per week that people
spend building apps. Yeah, it's a it's a
weird unique thing about I don't know
what you call that if that's enterprise
tooling or if it's developer tooling
specific, but it does feel like it's
unique compared to typical consumer
apps. It I do imagine it makes some
stuff a little harder like your
marketing can't be as honed in on one
specific thing, right? What is
interesting so at a certain point um and
I'll I'll share more details on it but
two friends joined me to to make it more
a mature company and one of them is head
of sales and he just tells me like it's
so easy to sell Rocket Sim and the
reason is and there are more examples of
apps like that Rocket Sim is focused on
reducing time spent and it creates more
time to work on actual features right
there are so many solved problems in the
world but if you manage to solve the one
limitation factor which time and give
more time to people, they will pay you
simply.
>> I mean, yeah, that's honestly that's one
of the biggest things with Revenue Cat
is uh it's like there's a lot of things
we can sell, but one of the easiest ones
is like exactly that same pitch. Like,
hey, nobody wants to make another
subscription management system that
everybody else has the same version of
or 12 iterations of the same payw wall
with slight differences. like let's let
the engineers get back to engineering
cool like stuff for users and then we'll
build all this tooling or let growth
people focus on this other stuff.
>> Totally. And I have conversations like
this about revenue get with some friends
that still don't use it by the way. You
know, like you you want to buy back.
>> No, there is no friends that don't use
it.
>> Yeah, sorry. Yeah, I can share the names
afterwards. There are many.
>> No, but I mean it's it's all about
buying back time, right? And yeah,
that's that's with everything. Like if
you do something repetitive every day,
you can solve that and make that like an
automation ideally so you don't have to
think about it anymore. You buy yourself
back five minutes a day, which is like
five multiplied by 365 per year. A lot
of time that you can spend on, you know,
growing your business, making that app
successful, right? It can make the
difference in a way.
>> So let's let's dive into that though.
So, like we talked about, you basically
by spending more time on features, you
were able to kind of grow the app. Um,
we won't get too deep into it, but
you've you can go go read your
newsletter uh if you want to learn more
about all the different like experiments
and and things that you've tried over
the years to sort of but I imagine all
most of those were pretty incremental.
But I guess you got to a point where you
could hire on help and was so the first
help you hired was on the on the sales
side.
>> Yeah. So at a certain point I wanted to
offer you know like a way to for teams
to buy multiple licenses at once because
the app store is in that sense limited.
This was a major point I wanted to bring
up because you talked so much about
being on the app store and sandboxed and
I see on your website I've never
consumed it this way but you that you
sell to teams and I don't I can't square
those two because for the most part the
app store is onetoone. So yeah how do
you do that? I see it a bit like a
Netflix subscription where you you might
have bought the subscription on the web,
right? And yeah, you log in on an iOS
app and your subscription still works.
It's a little bit like that for Rocket
Sim 2. But the the biggest point is that
we couldn't really offer Rocket Sim
easily to like a big team. And at that
point, I was like, okay, I want to do
it. So I was sitting with a friend from
the small village as well. He was a
front ender and I was like, "Hey, maybe
I I can use a front ender because I need
like a a back end." I had the idea of of
the teams dashboard that we have today
where the build durations of of your
whole team get together in a nice chart
and you can see like, "Hey, Charlie,
who's uh at revenue for years still has
an M1 MacBook, but somebody that just
joined has an M4." And you can see the
build duration being much faster. Give
insights and tell the whole team get a
M4 in two months, you you earn it back.
I needed a website for that right so I
was sitting with that front ender ask
him to join he was like yeah I want to
do something one day a week but I don't
really have a purpose so yeah let me
join and then similarly I had the
saleserson also a great friend for years
uh we wanted to have a side hustle
because we always challenge a bit each
other like how many how much money do
you make and you know sometimes you do
that with friends right and uh I was
like you need a side hustle right like
you need to do more things and yeah that
turned up to be you know join me uh
Also, it's also a great way to make sure
I always make more money than him. By
the way,
>> don't don't tell him. I hope he's not
listening. No, but no. Either way, um I
could I could use enterprise sales
knowledge, right? Or team sales
knowledge. And plus, I wanted to guard
my own time. I want to focus on
features. I don't want to focus on
selling. And same for the front end. I
could probably build a dashboard myself,
but there was no AI, right? Like maybe
today. Um no, no, I would I wouldn't
Nick Mick is doing a great job, Nick. Uh
I'm sure you're you're listening. So
>> yeah.
>> Well, and I will say the your like
landing page is exquisite. Uh it's very
very nice for like
>> showing how I don't know if that's
that's his work as well, but like it is
a
>> Yeah, it's extremely I was looking
because of AI tools. I was like ah I
should spend some time and redo mine and
I was looking at yours the other day
like
>> Yeah.
>> Oh, I could maybe use this. And I
started scrolling through and I'm like
maybe I could do something a little uh
less ambitious.
>> Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. Well,
>> it's very nice.
>> It's not that ambitious. The thing I
thought about is like my audience are
iOS developers, so I need to give it the
same feeling of watching the iPhone.
That's what it feels like. Yeah. Right.
Like the smooth animations and things
popping in and endless scrolling. And
>> honestly, we want to improve it. So,
there will be a new version for it, but
I don't think we will throw away that
that feeling of the homepage. But, um,
yeah. Either way, they they they wanted
to join me. And then at that point I was
also like yeah uh how do you do it in
terms of um dividing the money right
like Rocket Sim was there for six seven
years already I don't just want to give
them the money that I built up over the
years that felt unfair from my side it
felt unfair from their side so we um
decided to start a new venture basically
a venture of the three of us that get a
fixed price to buy a rocket sim license
from my company and is allowed to resell
it for any price so I'm basically
getting like a fixed But of that uh sold
license and everything above is divided
by a tree in a way.
>> And the way you you are doing like bulk
sales then is
through web web payments with like
license seats basically. And so if they
log in in Rocket Sim, it'll unlock that
based on their current enterprise
license.
>> Yeah, pre pretty much indeed. And um it
allows us to do direct invoicing. It
allowed us to uh you know like sell
commercial pricing which is higher which
you know at that point and it's funny
enough my monthly recurring revenue in
the app store slow down but the teams
you know it's I think at this point
almost equal or even past what uh what
we earn in the app store because we we
basically sell so much more and it's
difficult to get into companies but once
you're in we have some really big
clients once you're in then then they
basically just press a button and they
add 20 more seats, right? It goes so
fast and that's the real money for SAS
products. And it's al also fun, right?
Like Ralph and Nick are two friends of
mine for years and now we get to build
something together and we can also
celebrate things together. We've talked
about that on this show before with lots
of people, but like it is one of the
weirdest things about fully indie as in
solo development is like you can have a
big launch or you can have a big you
know you can get fireballed like end up
on on you know John Gruber can write
about you and it's like this extreme
moment of elation and then you're kind
of like sitting in your office you know
petting your dog like all right well
that was that and just having a group of
friends you can at the very least be in
a group chat and and celebrate together.
But especially if you're I don't know if
you all are in the same space, but like
if you can go out, if you can actually
celebrate with a person, it makes
everything feel a lot more uh like real.
>> Yeah. No, true. Yeah. Mik is nearby, but
Ralph lives in Atlanta in the United
States. Um which is also helpful for
>> small commute. Well, the funny thing is
he he joined me to Deep Dish last year.
Um, and also to do DC and we we managed
to get some deals signed there because
we met with with companies in person and
that feeling, you know, going out for
dinner and drinking a beer and going
crazy because you sold, you know, like
that's Yeah. unmatched and that's
definitely an great addition to being
indie mostly of the time. Yeah.
>> Oh, that's awesome. And before like we
we wrap up, I'm also curious, what are
your thoughts right now in terms of
the future of Rocket Sim in this sort of
crazy AI world that's sort of eating all
of our lunches, but RocketSim sort of
lives inside of this thing that's I
wouldn't say it's being sunk, but it's
being rocked around and nobody really
knows where it's it's going to land.
>> I mean, I I can clearly see that there
are so many more solutions nowadays,
right? Like we have the Xcode build MCP
for example and I believe it uses AXE
behind it to let agents use the
simulator and tools like those really
challenged me to think through the
future of Rocket Sim as well, right? And
I've had moments over the past months
where I started to integrate Rocket Sim
with agents. I had a MCP working and but
I was like well this is not the purpose
of Rocket Sim. I'm I'm sure Codeex or or
Cursor will do this themselves, right?
Like I will fight them and this is
probably not my purpose. What I do think
is that and and this is always hard to
really predict, right? But I believe how
much AI will write, there's always a
moment as a developer that you will test
the app and validate the outcome. That's
where I'm at at this point and I truly
believe in and if you think about Rocket
Sim today, that's exactly where we are
at because I don't help you write code.
I don't help you write better features.
I help you test the features quicker so
you can focus on writing the features.
And that that took me a bit to go back
and forth. And I'm not saying that
Rocket Sim will not integrate with
agents because I think there's value in
the data that we provide. In fact, we
recently allowed you to create prompts
outside of RocketSim or inside Rocket
Sim for the network request for example.
Give agents eyes on what your app is
doing in a way that only Rocket Sim can
do because we have that data in a way.
But mostly I think our mode or how you
want to call it is that we um we we
really help developers spend less time
validating all the things they need to
validate even though AI writes things.
And sure you can argue like well it's a
matter of time before AI will also do
that for you by automatically gaining
feedback visually or whatsoever. But I'm
not sure about you and maybe I'm
oldfashioned because I'm on developer
for years. I still want to be in control
myself and feel how it works and test
things out. So that that is my bet at
this point. And if I then combine it
with also connecting with agents, then
we have the two most powerful fundaments
I think for for a feature ahead. And
yeah, like for any app these days, you
need to remain flexible and move with
with the needle and see what's required,
what people need and and use AI to your
advantage. you know, don't let it eat
you, but make sure you eat with it in a
way, if that makes sense.
>> Yeah. Well, especially in in your case
because like, you know, if you're making
a consumer app, you do need to think
about the AI world, obviously in terms
of development, but in terms of your
users because chatbt could be a
competitor, right? Because it can do
everything theoretically, but like it
hasn't eaten the regular world the same
way that it's completely dominated
developers lives, but your customers are
are those people. And so uh and this is
where probably you spending the last how
many what is it like seven years of your
life writing and engaging directly with
the developer community is probably
super helpful. But it's like as new
needs are constantly coming up for
people and using these tools, you're
well primed to like see those,
anticipate them and build a tool that
makes it easier. And so it's like it
feels like a wave you could ride just as
much as be as be sunk by it.
>> So there is an interesting example. I
think two newsletter issues ago, I asked
my audience and I didn't get many
replies. Maybe because it's a feature
that people just don't realize they need
yet. But if you sometimes you test your
app and then you realize like, oh, damn
it, this is a bug. I I should not forget
to change this button color from blue to
red and we need to remind myself about
it. So you go to GitHub, you create the
issue or something like that or could
also be your QA engineer testing your
app in the simulator or a designer
validating your design. I figured like
this is where Rocket Sim can perfectly
be fitting, right? like you select an
element on the simulator and you write a
comment in the simulator and then you
prompt it straight ahead into codeex or
any AI that you use and there will just
be a PR open for review with a
screenshot attached for the developers
to review it and they're just a merge
away from fixing that color change and I
was like well this is something you want
right but I didn't really get much
response so I'm
>> well that feels like the type of feature
where people aren't going to know they
want that you have like show them the
way in in a sense and create that
demand.
>> And that's exactly my point, right? Like
we're in such weird situation now with
AI and many companies didn't really even
adopt AI, right? Like we're also
sometimes in a bubble where we feel like
everybody is using it already, but many
don't even know that agent skills exist
for example, right? That's also
something not to forget. And eventually
companies will have processes to adopt
AI and and security wise and so on and
so on. And then then I think developers
tools uh like Rocket Simu uh need to be
in a place that that fits that
perspective at that point.
>> Yeah, exactly. H well it's cool. It's it
was really fun talking about this. This
is I feel like you know I've been
reading your work and using Rocket Sim
for I mean essentially for the entirety
of me being an iOS developer. Uh so a
lot of this I knew but then little
little gaps I didn't know. So I don't
know. This is this is pretty cool and
it's well it honestly the way you're
talking about it sounds like it's more
fun to you. I know it can be uh a little
scary at times, but it it's been fun
watching you navigating the everanging
world and and figuring out where both
your
writing work and your, you know, your
app uh work fit into this this new
world. But one thing that you've always
done really well is articulate your
feelings and and your strategy very well
in a way that's sort of fun to follow
and and helps you think about, you know,
your own work in the same way.
>> Well, thanks. I appreciate it and I I
love that I can talk about the thing
that I love building the most. I don't
often get that opportunity to go in so
much detail about it. So, I appreciate
that a lot.
>> Before we wrap up, I'll ask you the
question uh I ask everybody in the show,
which is uh what's a person or people
out there that have inspired you and
your work that you'd recommend others
check out?
>> Yeah, there there's one mandatory thing
I have to say when you're part of the
DUPDC in the house, you have to say my
site or or you know, at least shout out
to those people. No, but honestly uh I
sometimes forget how uniquely talented
they are and how blessed I am that I get
to see what they're building from like a
nearby iMessage group and sometimes in
person. I thought about this question,
right? I listened to Lance. I knew that
it was coming. And there's one group,
those are Yodi, Ha, and Neils. Those are
indie developers from Amsterdam, from
the Netherlands as well. Uh Neils is in
Sweden nowadays, but they mean more to
me than they might realize, but they are
bold and honest. They're like friends
that tell you the truth. And I'm
reinventing myself constantly. I'm also
reinventing my socials and the work that
I do. And sometimes I make mistakes,
which I often regret. And sometimes I
don't realize I make mistakes. And they
are the honest friends that just tell me
upfront or they say like, "Hey, you're
now writing a little bit too much
clickbait on Twitter," for example,
right? I wanted I wanted to reach 5
million impressions because they can get
paid by by Twitter. And I was like,
okay, let's see if I can get that. And
and it made me realize like, yeah,
you're right. That's not who I am, who I
want to be. And I just highly appreciate
them. Plus the fact that they're amazing
developers. What they built is insane.
and and they just inspire me to
constantly keep pushing and deliver
amazing products. So yeah, when I
thought about this question, I just
can't live without them being on my side
even though it's just why I miss it
mostly.
>> Yeah, I have a really recent example of
of HA doing the same thing, you know,
pointing out a dumb thing that I was
doing and really calling me out on it.
People who who watched the previous
episode or maybe two episodes, I don't
remember the order that these will come
out, may have noticed my uh my facial
hair was, you know, getting to Antoine
levels. Maybe not quite, but it was on
its way.
>> So, you're now saying I I should have
shaved before. Damn it.
>> No, no, no, no, no. Uhhuh. No, we
released a I released a video. Actually,
it was for Revenue Cat. I released a
video that you could see a little bit of
facial hair going and uh and it just
goes, "Are you doing this for real or is
that AI?" And I was like, "No." I was
like, "It was it was just a short-term
thing." I shaved it and then he just
goes, "Thank God." And uh that confirmed
to me that uh I should never let this
grow out anymore anymore. that
>> but this is typical right I once had a
colleague who was really smelling but
will you you know say nothing and be
nice but you know that's also not really
helping him or will you confront him
with the matter allowing to improve but
it's also not really nice and
>> as a deeply insecure person uh there's
nobody in this world no colleagues in
this world I appreciate more than the
ones who are super direct uh which is
why I like working with Dutch people not
to you know lean into a stereotype but
having somebody who when you do
something dumb immediately tells you or
even when you don't do something dumb
but they think it's dumb. Having them
tell you right away makes at least me
feel a million times more secure around
them because I know like if I'm like oh
do they think this is dumb then I'm like
oh no if they thought it was it was dumb
they would have already told me. Uh that
is like a weirdly safe environment at
least for a person like me.
>> Oh man I wish everybody was like that.
Like people make mistakes right? Like
we're we're human and it's definitely
not always on purpose. So just be honest
to each other, try to help each other do
better. And I'm sure if those are good
friends of you, they will accept that
and be actually happy that you do so. So
yeah, absolutely. And those are three
friends that do that for me. So super
happy with them.
>> Awesome. All right. Well, uh, let's go
ahead and land this plane. So, uh, where
can people find you and your work?
>> Yeah. So, we mostly talked about Rocket
Sim. That's rocketsim.app. I'm sure
there will be links in the show notes,
but you know, a venderly.com is my
Swiftly blog where you can also
subscribe to my newsletter if you will
and on socials. It's all kind of
handles. I won't bother you listening to
that. Um, we'll make sure to put those
links in the the show notes and
>> definitely
>> yeah, make sure to um speak to me at
conferences. I'll be at a few. I'm
really social and I love to meet you
all. And if not, then uh I hope to
follow you somewhere else and meet you
somewhere else online.
>> All right, perfect. Uh, thank you
Antoine for coming on. And then I don't
know if you can see him, but my dog is
showing up to tell me this is a very
This is a very Antoine thing to do.
Actually, wasn't your profile picture
basically this for a long time?
>> Yeah.
>> Your dog's a lot taller than me, but
you're a lot taller than me, too. So,
maybe that's uh that's fair.
>> Maybe this is a good way to get more
people to subscribe to your YouTube
channel. I I'll get my dog, you know.
>> All right. You need to go down so I can
wrap this up. Okay, buddy. All right.
Right at the end. Uh oh. Oh, we're
getting the Oh, yeah. Here we go.
Here we are. Here he is. All right.
There we go. Here. Come on. Come on.
First ever launched uh dog segments. Uh
do you have any words, Moose, to say?
What is your dog's name again?
>> It's Benny.
>> Benny. All right. You want to say You
want to interview Benny?
>> Benny. Who's that?
>> Our editors are going to love dealing
with this. Actually, they probably will.
Who doesn't love seeing a dog, right?
>> Yeah, we'll do a loun episode with the
dogs, Jordan.
>> We should let them bark. We can
>> just release an hour and a half episode
of It's just them sitting there.
>> Yeah,
>> I was so close. I was so close to to
truly landing this, wasn't I? Uh
literally the very last thing to do. Uh
>> no, this is great. It It shows that
we're human, you know.
>> Exactly. We're not Exactly.
>> Okay. So again, thank you uh for coming
on. This was fun. Uh and thank you all
for listening. Uh launched is part of
the Revycat podcast family. If you'd
like to learn more about the growth side
of mobile app businesses, you should
check out SubCub uh hosted by my friend
and colleague uh David Barard. Um and of
course check out revikat.com to learn
about the easiest way to grow and
monetize your mobile app business. Uh,
for launch, you can go to launchfm.com
and uh, like Antoine, I won't read off
all of our handles, but for the most
part, it's launched fm basically
everywhere. And, uh, if you want to see
the dogs that may or may not have made
it into the edit, uh, you should check
out our YouTube channel. And, uh, and
you might see them or or you won't if
they didn't make it.
>> It's a good upsell.
>> Yeah. Yeah. Perfect. Exactly. Uh,
awesome. All right. Well, I will see you
all in two weeks. Bye.
>> Bye. Bye.